JESSICA ZHONG

Product Designer // San Francisco, CA

jessicajzhong@gmail.com
650-255-2187
in linkedin.com/in/jessicazhong

jessicazhong.design

SUMMARY

A Product Designer with a business acumen focused on people. I am committed to creating better user experiences through a deep understanding of people by identifying real-life problems and crafting thoughtful solutions grounded by research

EDUCATION

BLOC.IO

UX/UI Design Apprenticeship Nov 2018 - current

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO

B.S Management Science

SKILLS

DESIGN

UX/UI Design
Visual Design
User Research
Usability Testing
Brand Design & Identity
Information Architecture
Wireframing
Prototyping
Sketching

DESIGN TOOLS

Sketch

Figma

UsabilityHub

InVision

Draw.io

Maze

Craft

WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML

CSS

JavaScript (basic)

RECENT PROJECT

HEALTHPOINT | MOBILE APPLICATION

jessicazhong.design/project1.html

- A cloud-based mobile application that provides health enthusiasts an improved way to collect and store data, with the ability to analyze, connect and organize in the palm of their hand
- Utilized Sketch, Figma, Draw.io to create user flows, wireframes, mockups, usability testing and branding work

EXPERIENCE

BLOC.IO | UX/UI APPRENTICESHIP

Nov 2018 - Current

- Completing a 500+ hour immersive project-based online bootcamp under the mentorship of a senior UX professional
- Applying all design methodologies from user research, wireframes, mockups to functional prototypes using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Conducting user interviews and usability tests to gather feedback for creation of personas and iterations
- Developing brand identities, such as name, logo and style guide

JOBVITE | HR GENERALIST

Apr 2017 - Jan 2019

- Spearheaded company's first Wellness Initiative, resulting in a 45% participation rate across all programs for a company of 195 employees
- Implemented a candidate and new hire survey into Jobvite's platform to analyze tangible data regarding the health of Jobvite's brand and candidate experience
- Owned all aspects of onboarding new hire orientation, employment authorization, benefits enrollment to ensure a great employee onboarding experience

- Developed solutions for tasks related to employee relations, organizational restructuring, performance evaluations and operations
- Interpreted HR metrics and reporting analysis to create an evolving employee narrative for managers